A Finding Aid to the Solon H. Borglum and Borglum Family Papers, 1864-2002, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings and Notes, 1871-1983, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 2-3
  Writings and notes include those written by Solon Borglum and others. Writings and notes by Solon Borglum include project proposals for an Alexander Hamilton statue, the "Bells of History" project, and a sculpture only described as "The Grille." Also found are numerous essays by Solon and lecture notes on topics such as art, material and form, specific sculptural works, and his experiences in World War I. This series also includes Solon's notes on various subjects, including the founding of the School of American Sculpture and the Benjamin Franklin Monument project, and a diary with many sketches that Solon kept in 1918 during his military service. Similarly, Solon wrote in many notebooks during his time in the military and later career. The notebooks found here include personal thoughts, quotations, names and addresses, and sketches. Researchers will also find personal notes written in Solon's address books.
  Writings and notes by others include Emma Borglum's recollections on the life of Solon and their experiences together at the Crow Creek Reservation. Additional recollections on Solon Borglum are written by his daughter Monica Davies and her friend Josephine Sofio. Also found in this subseries is a lecture on Jacob Leisler, the subject of a Borglum sculpture, prepared by Monica's husband, A. Mervyn Davies, and a notebook kept by Emma's brother, Paul Vignal. Of interest are address lists and guest books for the various meetings of the Silvermine Group of Artists.
  Arrangement note
  The Writings and Notes series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  4.1: Writings and Notes by Solon Borglum, 1914-1922, undated
  4.2: Writings and Notes by Others, 1871-1983, undated
  - Writings and Notes by Solon Borglum, 1914-1922, undated; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Existence and Location of Copies
    The bulk of this series has been digitized.
    - Diary, 1917-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Loose Items From Diary, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Project Proposal, "Alexander Hamilton" sculpture, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Project Proposal, "Bells of History", Tentative Plan, circa 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Project Proposal, "Bells of History", Tentative Plan, circa 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Project Proposal, "Bells of History", Drafts and Notes, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Project Proposal, "Bells of History", Drafts and Notes, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Project Proposal, "Bells of History", Drafts and Notes, 1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Project Proposal, "The Grille", 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Essay, "The Duty of Art", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Essay, "The Duty of Art", Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Essay, "The Last Round-up", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Essay, "The Little Lady of the Dew", circa 1920; Archival Resource Key; (Partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Essay, "My Experience in the Great War", 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Essay, "The Province of a Sculptor", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Essay, "Reconstruction", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Lecture, Action and Speech, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Lecture, Appreciation and Style, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Lecture, Industrial Arts, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Lecture, "Inspiration and Aspiration", circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Lecture, "Inspiration and Aspiration", circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Lecture, Late Nineteenth-century French Artists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Lecture, "Presentation", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Notebooks, circa 1917-circa 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Notebooks, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Notes, Benjamin Franklin Monument, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Notes, New Canaan, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Notes, School of American Sculpture, circa 1919-1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Notes, School of American Sculpture, circa 1919-1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Notes, Silvermine Neighbors Club, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Partially scanned) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Address Books, circa 1917-circa 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Address Lists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Writings and Notes by Others, 1871-1983, undated; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    This series has not been digitized.
    - Emma Borglum, "An Account of the Life of Solon Borglum and the Experience at Crow Creek", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Emma Borglum, "An Account of the Life of Solon H. Borglum", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Emma Borglum, Essay on French Literature, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Emma Borglum, Recipe Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Emma Borglum, Recollections of Crow Creek, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Emma Borglum, Recollections of Crow Creek (in French), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - A. Mervyn Davies, Lecture on Jacob Leisler, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Monica Borglum Davies, "The Command of Got to Retreat", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Monica Borglum Davies, Recollections of Solon Borglum, 1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Josephine Sofio, Recollections of the Borglum Family, 1979, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Paul E. Vignal, Notebook of Quotations, 1871-1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Address List, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Address Lists, Miscellaneous, 1923, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Guest Books, Silvermine Group of Artists Meetings, circa 1910-1921, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1925, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Solon Borglum Biography, 1870-1975, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 5.3 Linear feet Box 3-8
  This series contains materials compiled or written by Monica Borglum Davies and her husband A. Mervyn Davies for the biography, Solon H. Borglum "A Man Who Stands Alone" (Pequot Press, 1974). Found here are numerous files of information gathered during the research process, including photocopies of materials such as correspondence, and documents from Solon's time in the military. Users should note that some of the photocopies of correspondence may overlap with material found in Family and General Correspondence (Series 2 and 3), however, many letters in this series include transcripts. Research files and notes also include lists of photographs, artwork, and students, as well as numerous loose notes, note cards and notebooks created in the process of writing the book. Also found in this series are other writings by Monica and A. Mervyn Davies giving background information and a synopsis of the biography project.
  The bulk of this series consists of heavily edited drafts of the biography. One subseries contains drafts of each section of the book. Researchers should note that many draft chapters do not correspond to or have different titles from the chapters in the published version. Another subseries includes draft manuscripts. All of the manuscripts are for the Borglum biography, but the authors were using various titles, including "A Clear Spirit," and "A Quiet Victory." Many drafts are incomplete and untitled, and the end of the series contains numbered loose pages from drafts and miscellaneous draft edits and notes, all arranged in their original order. Also found are two edited book proofs.
  The Solon Borglum Biography series is arranged into 4 subseries:
  5.1: Research Files and Notes, 1870-1975, undated
  5.2: Other Writings, undated
  5.3: Book Section Drafts, 1972-1973, undated
  5.4: Draft Manuscripts, 1970-1974, undated
  - Research Files and Notes, 1870-1975; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Descriptions of Works of Art, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Lists of Students and Acquaintences, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Lists of Photographs of Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Lists of Works of Art, 1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Note Cards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36-38)
    - Research Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39-47)
    - Research Notebooks, circa 1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
    - Family Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1870-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50-51)
    - Family Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1916-1962, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - General Correspondence, Photocopies and Transcripts, 1907-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - American Expeditionary Forces Documents, Photocopies, 1918-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Documents from the Library of Congress, Photocopies, 1903-1965, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, Photocopies, 1975, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Microfilm, The Hegsted Family, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Microfilm, Incomplete Collection of Newspaper Clippings, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Other Writings, undated; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    - "The Story of Project", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "The Two Sculptors Gutzon and Solon Borglum: A Continuing Confusion", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Synopsis of Biography, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Book Section Drafts, 1972-1973, undated; 5.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Title Page, 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Table of Contents, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - List of Illustrations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Author's Note, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Preface, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Forward, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Introduction, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - Acknowledgements, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Chapter I, 1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26-32)
    - Chapter II, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
    - Chapter III, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
    - Chapter IV, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Chapter V, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Chapter VI, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
    - Chapter VII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
    - Chapter VIII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
    - Chapter IX, 1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16-22)
    - Chapter X, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23-27)
    - Chapter XI, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28-31)
    - Chapter XII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32-34)
    - Chapter XIII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
    - Chapter XIV, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
    - Chapter XV, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Chapter XVI, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chapter XVII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chapter XVIII, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chapter XIX, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Chapter XX, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Epilogue, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chronology, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - References and Bibliography, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Index, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Gutzon Borglum Chapter, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Draft Manuscripts, 1970-1974, undated; 5.4; Archival Resource Key
    - "Art Upon a Larger Scale", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
    - "Art Upon a Larger Scale" Second Version, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - "Borglum the Sculptor", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
    - "The Borglum Story", Incomplete, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "A Clear Spirit", Incomplete, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - "A Quiet Victory", Synopsis and Select Chapters, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "A Quiet Victory", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Solon H. Borglum: A Man Who Stands Alone", 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25-28)
    - "Solon Hannibal Borglum", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "The Story of Two Brothers", Incomplete, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Untitled Draft, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Untitle and Incomplete Drafts, 1970-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7-14)
    - Numbered Loose Pages from Drafts, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15-28)
    - Miscellaneous Draft Edits and Notes, 1974, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-21)
    - Book Proof, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Book Proof, Second Copy, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Financial and Business Records, 1898-1998, undated; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 8, 13
  Financial and business records contain materials documenting Solon Borglum's professional work and legacy. Financial materials include bank account books, receipts and statements, ledgers, and price lists, as well as the financial notes and ledger for the Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund. Also found is a financial proposal for the 1905 Lewis and Clark Centennial, and an account book for the posthumous production and sales of Borglum's book Sound Construction. Business materials include contracts for sculpture projects, and copyright documentation for Sound Construction.
  Arrangement
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  The bulk of this series has not been digitized.
  - Account Book for Sound Construction, 1923-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Bank Account Books, 1903-1911, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Contracts for Sculpture Projects, 1906, 1910, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Copyright Documentation for Sound Construction, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Financial Notes, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1965-1980, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Financial Proposal, Lewis and Clark Centennial Project, circa 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ledger, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1961-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 2.
  - Ledgers, 1898-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31-32)
  - Legal Documents, Solon Borglum Estate, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Price Lists, 1924, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Receipts and Statements, 1903-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Ledger, Solon H. Borglum Sculpture and Education Fund, 1961-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 8, Folder 30.
- Printed Material, 1879-2002, undated; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Box 9, 13-14
  This series contains material on Solon Borglum's career and artwork, primarily posthumous exhibit materials and publications. Most of this material was collected by Solon's daughter Monica Borglum Davies and includes not only material on Solon, but also documents about Gutzon, Solon's assistant Paul Manship, and the Silvermine Group of Artists. Included are auction catalogs, exhibition announcements, catalogs, brochures, event programs, and informational booklets. Also found are numerous news and magazine clippings spanning over 120 years, magazines featuring large articles on Solon, newletters, press releases, reports, and other publications as well as published images of Solon and reproductions of his artwork. This series also contains copies of the art textbook Solon wrote, Sound Construction, as well as the Supplement for this work published at the same time.
  Series is partially digitized.
  - Auction Catalogs, 1964, 1974, 1983, 1988; Archival Resource Key; (partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Brochures, 1900, 1921, 1961-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, School of American Sculpture, 1921-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, undated; 1897-1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1907-1921; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1924-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1974-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1983-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Solon Borglum, 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Gutzon Borglum, 1889-1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
  - Clippings, Silvermine Group of Artists, undated; 1910-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, Silvermine Group of Artists, 1968-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1879-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16-23)
  - Essay, Phil Kovinick, "South Dakota's 'Other' Borglum", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Event Programs, 1905, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Silvermine Group of Artists, 1915-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Architectural Exhibition of the Cleveland Architectural Club, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Gutzon Borglum, 1905, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Paul Manship, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Silvermine Guild of Artists, 1910, 1946, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Solon H. Borglum, 1966-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - German Army Songbook, 1897; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Images of Solon Borglum, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Informational Booklets, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Magazine, The Century, vol. 99, no. 2, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Magazine, Illustrated American, vol. 5, no. 50, 1891; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Magazine, The Kennedy Quarterly, 1962, 1965, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous, 1922, 1976, 1999; Archival Resource Key; (partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Map of Kensico Cemetery, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 39)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 3.
  - Newsletters, 1972, 1974, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Newspaper, Decatur-Dekalb News, "Stone Mountain Dedication Special Edition", 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 41)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 4.
  - Postcards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Press Releases, Stone Mountain Memorial Dedication, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Publication, "Celebrating the 50th Anniversary of the Silvermine Guild of Artists", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 44)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 13, Folder 5.
  - Publication, Historical Biography and Libretto of the Indian Congress, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 45)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 6.
  - Publication, La Defense De Verdun, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 46)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 7.
  - Report of the American E. F. Art Training Centre, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Report of the Gordon Monument Commission, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Solon Borglum, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 49-50)
    Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 8.
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, 1891, 1875, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 52)
    Oversized material housed in Box 14.
  - Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, unbound version, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 53)
    2 copies; oversized material housed in Box 14.
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon H. Borglum, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Supplement to Sound Construction by Solon Borglum, unbound version, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1914-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Map of Kensico Cemetery, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 9, Folder 39.
  - Newspaper, Decatur-Dekalb News, "Stone Mountain Dedication Special Edition", 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)